Guide to the Mitchell-Tiffany Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- FINANCIAL, LEGAL AND HOUSEHOLD PAPERS OF ALFRED AND ANNIE O. MITCHELL, 1887-1935; Series II; 2 linear feet (6 boxes)
  - Annie O. Mitchell Trust (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Stock certificates of Alfred Mitchell, 1841-1880 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Tiffany and Company stockholders' notices, 1920-1924 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence and memoranda related to the house built in New Haven by Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell, 1908-1909, n. d. (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Materials relating to the "Folly" estate, Port Antonio, Jamaica, 1920-1922, n. d. (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Architectural plans of 72nd Street house in New York (Box 39, Folder 79)
      See: Common Folio, box 4, folder 79
    - Household account book, 1874-1880 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Household account books. Salem, Connecticut, kept by Alfred Mitchell, 1903-1905, n. d. (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - Household account book, Jamaica
      - 1906 - 1910 (Box 12, Folder 49-50)
    - Household record book of Jamaican servants' wages, 1905-1915 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Household record books of American servants' wages, 1908-1912 (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - Household inventory books, 1903-1909? (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Household inventories, 1902-1920, n. d. (Box 13, Folder 54)
    - Household memoranda, 1900-1918, n. d. (Box 13, Folder 55)
    - Receipts of purchases made during trip to Europe, 1865-1866 (Box 13, Folder 56)
    - Bryn Mawr College bills of Charly Tiffany Mitchell, 1894-1897 (Box 13, Folder 57)
    - Receipts of purchases made during trip to Japan, 1899 (Box 13, Folder 58)
    - Shipping invoices of articles purchased in Japan, 1899 (Box 13, Folder 59)
    - Japanese business cards, drawings of items for sale, 1899 (Box 13, Folder 59)
    - Storage receipts, 1891-1916, n. d. (Box 13, Folder 60)
    - Receipts of purchases made in Jamaica
      - 1906 - 1912 (Box 13, Folder 61-64)
    - Receipts (Box 13, Folder 61-64)
      - 1864 - 1911 (Box 13, Folder 65-69)
      - 1912 - 1931 (Box 14, Folder 70-73)
    - Bills from French dressmakers
      - 1902 - 1909, undated (Box 14, Folder 74-75)
- DIARIES AND WRITINGS OF ALFRED AND ANNIE O. MITCHELL, 1860-1929; Series III; 1.5; (3 boxes)
  Series III consists of diaries, memoranda books, articles and note-books. The materials are grouped by author and by type, and are arranged chronologically within each category.
  - Diary, kept by Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell
    - 1865 January - 1867 May (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
    - 1896, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1913-1915 (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
    - 1915 - 1919, 1918 - 1922 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - 1923 - 1926, 1927 - 1929 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Memoranda books, kept by Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell
    - 1867 - 1895 (Box 16, Folder 9-17)
  - Notes on family history by Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell, n. d. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Diary, kept by Alfred Mitchell, 1906-1910 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - "Forty Days on a Guano Island," by Alfred Mitchell, post 1860 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - "The Cultivation of Coffee in the State of Guatemala," by Alfred Mitchell, 1868 November 6 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - The Story of Sibylle, by Octave Feuillet, translated by Alfred Mitchell for Hearth and Home, 1869 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - "Natural History of the Folly," notebook and clippings concerning the plants of Jamaica, compiled by Alfred Mitchell, 1910? (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Regimental roll book of Alfred Mitchell, 1863 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Memoranda book [kept by Miss Miller?], 1911 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Memoranda book [kept by Miss Miller?], 1912 (Box 17, Folder 26)
- PERSONAL AND BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS RELATING TO ALFRED AND ANNIE O. MITCHELL, 1853-1925; Series IV; 1 linear foot (2 boxes)
  Series IV consists of school catalogs, notebooks, passports, invitations, gift lists, visitors' cards, obituaries and newspaper clippings and is arranged by individual and by type of material.
  - Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell
    - Juvenilia, 1853-1866 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Catalogues of the Wheaton Female Seminary, 1855-1858 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Programs of Mademoiselle Rostan's Young Ladies Institute, 1859 May-June (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Report card, 1863 April 15 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Mathematics notebooks, 1855, 1857, n. d. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Student compositions, 1857-1859 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Penmanship and poetry notebooks, 1859, n. d. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "Kings of England," notebook, 1861? (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - French notebooks, 1862, n. d. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Thought Exchange," notebook, 1870 March (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Materials relating to the marriage of Alfred and Annie O. Mitchell, 1871 April 27 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Christmas lists, 1906-1922 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Address book, Circa 1930-1932 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Passports, 1915, 1916, 1928 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Personal notes, Red Cross certificate and measurement records, 1857-1926, n. d. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Programs, calling cards and printed matter, 1864-1883, 1925-1926, n. d. (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Visitors cards, Europe, 1865-1866 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Visitors cards, Madeira, 1883? (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous visitors cards, n. d. (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Alfred Mitchell
    - Passport, 1861 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Appointment as Major of the 13th Regiment of Volunteers of Connecticut, 1863 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Personal notes and pamphlets, 1857, 1878-1882, n. d. (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Obituaries (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Resolution issued by Tiffany and Co. on the death of Alfred Mitchell, 1911 May 9 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper clippings relating to Mitchell, Tiffany and Bingham relatives (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Newspaper clippings relating to the Lucretia Shaw papers and Florida (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1859-1931, undated (Box 19, Folder 24-25)
    - Clippings scrapbook of Alfred Mitchell, 1889-1908 (Box 19, Folder 26)
- PAPERS OF OTHER FAMILY MEMBERS, 1803-1927; Series V; 4 linear feet (9 boxes)
  Series V consists of letters, legal documents, financial records, sermons, writings and newspaper clippings. The papers of individual family members are arranged alphabetically by name, with letters filed with the recipient's papers. The individuals whose papers are contained in this series are members of the Mitchell, Tiffany, Woodbridge, Mumford, Bingham, Jeans, Perkins, Young, and Thatcher families.
  - Bingham, Alfreda (Mitchell) (1874-1967)
    - Letters from Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell and Alfred Mitchell, 1882-1908, n. d. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Charly Tiffany (Mitchell) Jeans, 1883-1898, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Letters from May (Tiffany) Lusk, 1881-1887, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Letters from Donald Grant Mitchell, 1888-1894 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Letters addressed jointly to Alfred and Charly Mitchell, 1883-1888, n. d. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - General correspondence, 1880-1908 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Juvenilia, 1874-1899, undated (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
    - Wedding announcement and invitation lists, 1900 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Bingham, Hiram III (1875-1956): Letter from Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell, 1908 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Grant, Donald: Passport, 1732 April 14 (Box 39)
    See: Folio 1
  - Jeans, Charly Tiffany (Mitchell) (1877-1934)
    General note
    Letters from Annie O. (Tiffany) Mitchell and Henry Russell
    Newspaper clippings
    Letter from Alfreda (Mitchell) Bingham
    - Letters from Alfreda (Mitchell) Bingham, 1895-1896, 1902 (Box 20, Folder 11-12)
    - Letters from Annie O., (Tiffany) Mitchell (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - General correspondence, 1883-1922 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Juvenilia, 1883-1891, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Bryn Mawr College examination papers, 1890-1898 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Bryn Mawr College materials, 1894-1898, undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Wedding announcement and invitation lists, 1907 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Poem, 1911 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - List of trunk contents, 1907 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Jeans, James (1877-1946), 1921, undated, 1927-1932 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Lusk, Mary (Tiffany) (1873-?), 1896 January 5 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Mitchell, Rev. Alfred (1790-1831)
    Mitchell (1794-1839) and Stephen Mix
    Mitchell (1743-1835)
    - Letters from Lucretia M (Woodbridge), 1814-1818, undated (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Sermons, 1821-1824 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Sermons, 1827 - 1828 January (Box 21, Folder 24-25)
    - Sermons, 1828 March-August (Box 21, Folder 26-28)
    - Sermons, 1828 October-December (Box 21, Folder 29-30)
    - Sermons, 1829 January-February (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Sermons, 1829 April-September (Box 21, Folder 32-35)
    - Sermons, 1829 November 8-15 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Sermons, 1829 November 22-29 (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Sermons, 1829 December (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Sermons, 1830 January-September (Box 22, Folder 39-43)
    - Sermons, 1830 November-December (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Sermons, 1831 January-April (Box 22, Folder 45-46)
    - Sermons, 1831 June-July (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Sermons, 1831 Aug, Oct, undated (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous personal and biographical materials, 1809-1843 (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - Mitchell, Lucretia M. (Woodbridge) (1794-1839)
    - Financial and legal papers, 1805-1839, undated (Box 22, Folder 50-51)
    - Record book of the distribution of Rev. Alfred Mitchell's estate, under the guardianship of William Williams, 1839-1853 (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - Mitchell, Donald Grant (1822-1908) (Box 23, Folder 52)
    - Letters from Lucretia M. (Woodbridge) Mitchell, 1831-1839 (Box 23, Folder 53-55)
    - Letters from other family members, 1838-1840 (Box 23, Folder 56)
    - General correspondence, 1846-1870, undated (Box 23, Folder 57)
    - "A Report to the Commissioners on Lay-out of East Rock Park", 1882 (Box 23, Folder 58)
      See also: Folio 2
      - Oversized maps of Edgewood area, Undated (Box 40)
    - Hearth and Home (21 issues), 1869 January-Feb, July-December
      See: Box 27, folder 110
    - Financial and legal papers, 1855-1870 (Box 23, Folder 59)
      - Oversize, 1855-1868 (Box 39)
        See also: Folio 1
    - Financial and legal papers, 1871-1902, undated (Box 23, Folder 60)
      - Oversize, 1873-1902 (Box 39)
      - Certificates of appointment as Consul of Venice, 1853-1854 (Box 39)
    - Catalogue d'Ouvrages Relatifs à l'Histoire de Venise, 1853 (Box 23, Folder 61)
    - Newspaper clippings and obituaries, 1895-1908 (Box 23, Folder 62)
  - Mitchell, Elizabeth [daughter of Donald Grant Mitchell], 1886-1921 (Box 23, Folder 63)
  - Mitchell, Hannah (Grant): Letter from Rev. Alfred Mitchell, 1820 (Box 23, Folder 64)
  - Mitchell, Harriet
    - Letters from Rev. Alfred Mitchell, 1810-1815 (Box 23, Folder 65)
    - Legal papers, 1836-1868 (Box 23, Folder 65)
      - Oversize, 1838 April 2 (Box 39)
  - Mitchell, Louis (1826-1881)
    - Correspondence, 1862-1881 (Box 23, Folder 66)
    - Receipts, 1841-1846 (Box 23, Folder 66)
  - Mitchell, Lucretia M. (Woodbridge) (1794-1839) (Box 23, Folder 66)
    Letters
    Legal papers
    Biographical information
    - Letters from Rev. Alfred Mitchell, 1814-1820 (Box 23, Folder 67)
    - Letters dealing with the sale of land in Ohio, 1833-1836 (Box 23, Folder 68)
    - General correspondence, 1831-1833 (Box 23, Folder 69)
    - Sample of penmanship, n. d. (Box 23, Folder 70)
    - Miscellaneous legal documents found among her papers, 1760, 1824, 1835 (Box 23, Folder 71)
    - Mitchell, Stephen Mix (1743-1835), 1806, 1822, 1803-1819, 1877 (Box 24, Folder 72)
  - Mitchell, Stephen Mix (1818-1839
    - Letters from Rev. Alfred Mitchell, 1831 (Box 24, Folder 73)
    - Household accounts, 1838-1839 (Box 24, Folder 74-75)
  - Mitchell, Walter (1777-1849)
    Letter from Donald Grant Mitchell
    Letters from Lucretia M. (Woodbridge)
    Mitchell
    Letters from Rev. Alfred Mitchell,
    Lucretia (Woodbridge) Mitchell, and Stephen Mix Mitchell
    Letters from Lucretia (Woodbridge)
    Mitchell and Louis Mitchell
    Letter from Charly (Mitchell) Jeans
    - Correspondence, 1838-1848 (Box 24, Folder 76)
    - Legal and financial papers, 1816-1844 (Box 24, Folder 77)
      - Oversize, 1816, 1838 (Box 39)
    - Legal and financial papers, 1845-1850 (Box 24, Folder 78)
      - Oversize, 1846 April 30 (Box 39)
    - Mitchell, Walter (1873-?), 1888 August 21 (Box 24, Folder 79)
    - Mumford, Lucretia (Christophers) (1750-1825), n. d. (Box 24, Folder 80)
    - Perkins, Elias, 1830, 1838 (Box 24, Folder 81)
    - Perkins, Mary, 1812, 1815? (Box 24, Folder 82)
    - Perkins, Nathaniel S., 1811, 1812, 1849 (Box 24, Folder 83)
    - Perkins, Thomas Shaw, 1836-1837 (Box 24, Folder 84)
    - Piatt, Julia C. G., 1915 (Box 24, Folder 85)
    - Thatcher, Lucretia, n. d. (Box 24, Folder 86)
    - Tiffany, Burnett Young (1860-?) Passport, 1887 (Box 24, Folder 87)
  - Tiffany, Charles Lewis (1812-1902)
    Tiffany, Katrina (Ely) (1875-1927)
    Letters from Mitchell and Bingham relatives
    - Correspondence, 1863-1902 (Box 24, Folder 88)
    - Letters concerning 50th wedding anniversary, 1891 November-December (Box 24, Folder 89)
    - Letters concerning 87th birthday, 1899 February (Box 24, Folder 90)
    - Invitations, programs, bills and receipts, 1863-1865, 1894 (Box 24, Folder 91)
    - Charles L. Tiffany and the House of Tiffany and Company, and newspaper clippings, 1893 (Box 24, Folder 92)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1868-1900 (Box 24, Folder 93)
    - Obituaries and funeral notices, 1902 (Box 24, Folder 94)
      See also: Box 27a, folder 111
    - Tiffany, Charles Lewis II (1878-?), 1901-1905 (Box 25, Folder 95)
  - Tiffany, Harriet O. A. (Young) (1813-1897)
    - Letters from Charles L. Tiffany, 1863, 1865 (Box 25, Folder 96)
    - Correspondence, 1864-1870 (Box 25, Folder 97)
    - Funeral service text, 1897 (Box 25, Folder 97)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1860, undated (Box 25, Folder 97)
  - Tiffany, Louis Comfort (1848-1933)
    - Correspondence, 1861-1886, 1908 (Box 25, Folder 98)
    - Printed matter, clippings and drawing, 1903-1925 (Box 25, Folder 99)
    - Reprint, "Louis Comfort Tiffany Photographer-In-Charge," History of Photography, v. 4, no. 4, 1980 October (Box 25, Folder 99a)
    - Young, Lydia B. (Box 25, Folder 100)
    - Correspondence, 1866 (Box 25, Folder 100)
    - Miscellaneous letters, n. d. (Box 25, Folder 101)
    - The Woodbridge Record compiled by Louis Mitchell and Donald Grant Mitchell, 1883 (Box 25, Folder 102)
    - A record of recipients of copies of the Woodbridge Record, Circa 1883 (Box 25, Folder 102a)
    - "The Genealogy of the Woodbridge Family," notebook, n. d. (Box 25, Folder 103)
      - Oversized genealogical materials, Undated (Box 40)
    - Woodbridge family genealogical materials and a map of Groton, CT (Box 26, Folder 104)
    - Papers used by Mary E. Perkins in preparation of Chronicles of a Connecticut Farm, 1769-1905, n. d. (Box 26, Folder 105-109)
    - Mitchell, Donald Grant (1822-1908) Hearth and Home (21 issues), 1869 January-Feb, July-December (Box 27, Folder 110)
    - Tiffany, Charles Lewis (1812-1902) In Memoriam: Charles Lewis Tiffany, February 18, 1902 [oversize album] (Box 27a, Folder 111)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1850-1910; Series VI; 9.5 linear feet (11 boxes)
  Series VI consists of photographs of family members and friends, photograph scrapbooks of Alfreda Mitchell, and photograph albums of Alfred Mitchell. They are arranged by form and by size.
  - Individual photographs
    - Alfred Mitchell, Circa 1895-1910 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Alfred Mitchell and Donald G. Mitchell, Circa 1895 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Annie O. Mitchell (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Louis Mitchell (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Julia C. Piatt (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Charles Lewis Tiffany and Harriet (Young) Tiffany (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Other family members and friends (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Photograph scrapbook of Alfreda Mitchell, 1882-1890 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Photograph scrapbook of Alfreda Mitchell, 1885-1892 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Photograph albums of Alfred Mitchell
    - Descriptive lists of albums, by Alfred M. Bingham, 1977-1978 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - "Madeira, Portugal, Biscaya, Navarre" (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - "Portraits" (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - "Family History," vol. I (Box 29A, Folder 13)
    - "Family History," vol. II (Box 29B, Folder 14)
    - "Family History," vol. III (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - "Family History," vol. IV (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - No folder (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - "New Orleans, Florida, Charleston, Jamaica, Cuba" (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - "California", 1885 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - "Mexico", 1898 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - "Paris, Florence, Sorrento, Venice" (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - "Siena, Florence, Lakes, Riviera, Holland, Nassau" (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - "Egypt", 1895-1896 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - "Egypt, Southern Italy, Lakes, Art", 1895-1896 (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Photograph albums: professional photographs (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - "Millet collection of Japanese photos" (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Reproductions of Renaissance Art, Circa 1866 (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Album 1: Black ribbed leather album, 2 tooled clasps., 1860-1890 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    Page 1: C. L. Tiffany & wife; Louis Page 2: Bernie; Louise Page 3: Uncle John; Aunt Lydia Page 4: Mrs. Ogden Hoffman; Mary Hoffman Page 5: Ginnie Hoffman; Dr. Geo. Potts, Pastor of 10th St. Church Page 6: James Dunham; James Dunham & wife (Cousin Lottie Morse) Page 7: Nellie McClure; Lizzie Townsend Page 8: Miss Bullock with 4 girls, 1 man; Aunt Trembly Page 9: Louise Nettleton; Mr. Hollingshead Page 10: Louise Nettleton, Mary Huntington, Annie O. Tiffany and unidentified woman; Daughter of Jared Sparks Page 11: Mr. Content (?) Cousin Hattie Backus; Fanny Hazeltine Page 12: Auntie and Mrs. Almy; A. H. Almy Page 13: Dr. Kirker of Philadelphia; Grace Townsend Page 14: Henry Goodard; May Goodard Page 15: Len Almy and his father; Unidentified woman Page 16: Riggs of Washington (Mrs.); Annie O. Tiffany [?] Page 17: Mr. de Horrock; Mrs. de Horrock of Mobile, Alabama Page 18: Ellen Amelia Hutchins; Libby Stedman Page 19: Mr. Phillips; Louise Nettleton, Mary Hoffman, Mary Huntington, Annie O. Tiffany; Lottie Van Schoonborn, Lansingburg, New York Page 20: Mr. Doramieux; Eliza Gardner Page 21: General Anderson; 3 daughters of General Anderson Page 22: Julia Tucker; Emile Kingsland Page 23: George McClure; Aunt Maria McC. Page 24: Baby girl; Emily Coles, Catskill Page 25: Uncle Ebben Young; Mama Page 26: D'Oramin and children; Gertrude Holbrook, Chicago Page 27: Geo. Gaurault; Mary Huntington Page 28: Edw. Dunham; Mary Porter Page 29: Ida Deacon; Len Almy Page 30: Judge Morse; Mrs. Morse Page 31: Tyler; Mary Tyler
  - Album 2: Small (4"x 5 1/2") black leather album (Box 36, Folder 28)
    Page 1: "Men of Norwich. By their works shall ye know them." Page 2: Governor Buckingham Page 3: Brigadier General D. Tyler Page 4: Brigadier General Ed. Harland Page 5: H. W. Birge. bvt Major General Page 6: Wm. G. Ely, Colonel 18th Connecticut Volunteers Page 7: Colonel J. E. Ward. 18th Connecticut Volunteers Page 8: A. P. Rockwell, Colonel 6th Connecticut Volunteers Page 9: C. Goddard, Lieutenant Colonel ADC. United States Volunteers Page 10: C. Farnsworth, Lieutenant Colonel, V.C. Cavalry Page 11: Major F. S. Bond. ADC Page 12: N. Fisher, Surgeon 13th Connecticut Volunteers Page 13: Wm. T. Lusk, Captain, Assistant Adjutant General Page 14: Chas. Coit, Major 8th Connecticut Volunteers Page 15: A. Mitchell, Major 13th Connecticut Volunteers, New Orleans photo. Page 16: Captain James J. McCord, l3th Connecticut Volunteers Page 17: Captain H. P. Goddard, 14th Connecticut Volunteers Page 18: R. A. Ripley, Captain 13th Connecticut Volunteers Page 19: Lieutenant Marvin Wait, 18th Connecticut Volunteers. Killed at Antietam, September 17, 1862 Page 20: G. W. Whittlesey, Adjutant 13th Connecticut Volunteers Page 21: Jno. O. Abbot, Lieutenant 13th Connecticut Volunteers Page 22: Alfred Mitchell Goddard, Lieutenant 8th Connecticut Volunteers (1835-1863) Page 23: J. Spofford, Sergeant Major 8th Connecticut Volunteers Page 24: Alfred Mitchell. Paris photo, later, in great coat.
  - Album 3: Album; brass & leather binding (Box 36, Folder 28)
    Page 1: Christmas card, hand painted: "Annie O. Tiffany, Christmas '64 LT" Page 2: "Mama" 1864 Harriet Young Tiffany Page 3: "Papa" Charles L. Tiffany Page 4: "Louise" Louise H. Tiffany, age 8 Page 5: "Louis" Louis Comfort Tiffany, age 16 Page 6: "Burnie" Burnett Young Tiffany, age 4 Page 7: Mrs. Ogden Hoffman Page 8: "Aunt Lydia" Lydia Almy (Mrs. John B.) Young Page 9: "Uncle John" B. Young Page 10: "Fred. Peck" (husband of Aunt Ellen Young) Page 11: "Uncle Morse," Brooklyn. (Judge Nathan Brewster Morse, husband of Aunt Eliza Tiffany.) Page 12: Burnie & Louise Page 13: "Uncle Henry Tiffany" William Henry Tiffany 1819-1880 Page 14: "Stannie Hager" (Stansbury Hager, b. 1871?, grandson of Aunt Harriet Tiffany Tremblay) Page 15: Henry Goddard 1842-1880 (in Civil War uniform, Cousin of Alfred Mitchell) Page 16: Newton Perkins Page 17: Lili (?) Perkins Page 18: Nel Peck (age 5?) Page 19: Alice Peck (age 7?) Page 20: Mrs. Almy Page 21: Mr. Almy (brother of Aunt Lydia Young) Page 22: Mrs. Hutchins, Paris Page 23: George P. Clapp Page 24: Samuel Valentine Page 25: Ella Norton, Norwich Page 26: Mollie Davenport Page 27: Dr. Erving Mears, Philadelphia Page 28: "Pinkie" Pomeroy Page 29: Agnes Pomeroy & little sister, Pitsfield, Massachusetts Page 30: ? Dows (?) Page 31: Archie Hazard (?) Page 32: Mrs. Hazard Page 33: Mr. Hazard Page 34: Group of 6, Paris photo. "Dons" & "Hazard" identified Page 35: Group of 9 identified on back; Thursday Sept. 7th/66, Cedar Point, Irvington, New York: 1.Louis C. Tiffany 2.Edward Coffin 3.May Goddard 4.Harry P. Gray 5.Fred Terry 6.Emile Kingsland 7.Nellie Collins (Hartford) 8.Annie O. Tiffany 9.Henry P. Goddard Page 36: Henry P. Goddard, in sportswear "Uncas" on belt, holding croquet ball, Norwich photo. Page 37: Nellie (?) Slater Page 38: Mr. & Mrs. Stockwell Page 39: Emile Kingsland, Boston-Newport photographer, 1865 Page 40: Nellie McClure (daughter of Aunt Maria Young) Page 41: Mr. Lockwood, Paris Page 42: Louise Ruch (?) Paris photographer Page 43: Cousin Brewster Morse, 7th Regiment uniform Page 44: "With the compliments of Gardner Cottrell USN" "Lieut." Nice photographer Page 45: Cottrell's ship "with the compliments of" etc. Page 46: Mary & Nellie Tyler, Philadelphia (ages 8,3 ?) Page 47: Henry Peters Gray, Jr. in dress uniform. Brady photo Page 48: Mr. Tait, New York Page 49: BLANK Page 50: Emile Kingsland (tin-type) Page 51: Sam Valentine (tin-type)
  - Album 4: Small black album with metal clasp (Box 37, Folder 29)
    Album contains 45 pictures of famous individuals in government, the military, religion and the arts. Mostly from the nineteenth century.
    No Album 5
  - Album 6: Album, tooled leather binding, brown (Box 37, Folder 30)